All right, folks, in this clip I'm going to teach you how to draw a cartoon character with a gloomy expression.
And we'll move right down here to this lower corner here.
And we'll start with the eyes.
And one thing we're going to do kind of differently about this guy is we're going to definitely sell the gloomy look by making his eyebrows very, very low.
Just like that.
Almost to the bottom of his eyes there.
Come in here and draw his nose very quick.
And the pupils will be just barely hanging below the lids there.
Then we'll come up here and we'll kind of give him sort of a sad eyebrow expression with them, just slightly pointed upwards.
Just like that.
And to really sell the whole gloomy look, we're going to make his mouth hanging extra low and kind of small.
Not very big.
Really small, sort of a little lips expression.
That just looks gloomy.
And you can add other things by making his face kind of look longer like that, instead of the usual perky way that I usually do it.
Not a lot of perkiness in this guy's face right now.
So, those are the visual clues for the audience that this guy isn't feeling all that great.
The eyes being long and low.
The mouth being small.
The eyebrows being up.
And that definitely gives away the fact that this particular character is feeling rather low and gloomy.